hello everyone! Welcome to the hope bay bridge channel
大家好！欢迎收看 HopeBayBridge 频道
Today, I'm with you
今天我跟大家一起
Take a look at how to configure it correctly
看一看如何正确的配置
environment variable
环境变量
Operating system efficiency of environment variables
环境变量对于操作系统的运行效率
Especially important
尤为重要
Correct configuration can improve their operation efficiency
正确的配置才能使它们的运行效率得到提高
First let's take a look
首先我们看一下
How to be correct on win10 system
在Win10系统上如何正确的
to configure
配置
environment variable
环境变量
We found
我们找到
computer
计算机
Right mouse button
鼠标右键
Click Properties
点击属性
And then choose the system
然后再选择这个系统
Advanced system settings
高级系统设置
And click on it
并且点击它
then
然后
Let's click environment variable again
我们再点击环境变量这个按钮
hereunder
在下面
namely
就是
system
系统
variable
变量
These are
这些就是
Configuration of the local operating system
本地操作系统的配置的
programmatic
程序的
catalog
目录
We found the path
我们找到path
edit
编辑
You'll see
就会看到
This one by one program directory
这一个一个的程序的目录
Put you in the local
将你在本地
Installed
安装好的
Program directory
程序目录
We build
我们新建
after
之后
Put it here
放在这里
Click OK after placement
放置好之后点确定
That's it
就可以了
as for
至于
Win7
Win7
system
系统
It could be
可能是
Not in this form
不是这种形式
You need to pay attention
大家需要注意
Add ";"
加";"
English symbols
英文符号
English ";"
英文";"
this
这
I configured it on disk e
我配置的是在E盘
When you install the program, try not to install it in
大家在安装程序的时候尽量不要安装在
programmatic
程序的
Systematic
系统的
operation
操作
Disk: "C disk"
磁盘：“C盘”
Install the other drive letter
安装那其他的盘符
Otherwise, it will get more and more stuck
不然时间久了会越来越卡（顿）
I put it on this "e disk"
我放在这个"E盘"
Just
就
copy
复制
This directory
这个目录
To what I just said
到我刚才说的
environment variable
环境变量
newly build
新建
cancel
取消
edit
编辑
We found "pathu201c
我们找到“path"
newly build
新建
Just put it here and make sure
放在这里,点确定就好了
Because I have already configured it, cancel this point
因为我已经配置过了,这点取消
Next, click the OK button
接下来再点确定按钮
That's it
就可以了
You can also configure a
大家也可以配置一个
image
像
JAVA_ HOME
JAVA_HOME
JMETER_ Home, prefix like this
JMETER_HOME,这样的前缀
Then find "path"
之后再找到"path"
edit
编辑
Put this
将这个
JAVA_ Home variable
JAVA_HOME变量
After the "%" sign in front of the place
放点前面加“%”号之后
Add at the back
后边加上
"Bin" directory
“bin"目录
That's it
就可以了
such
这样
The environment variables of windows series
Windows系列的环境变量就
It's configured
配置好了
Let's take a look at Mac
接下来我们再看一下Mac
And Linux
以及Linux
How to configure
如何配置
environment variable
环境变量
Next, let's turn on the Mac
接下来我们打开Mac系统
Folder found
找到文件夹
Find your home directory
大家找到自己的主目录
MAC system
Mac系统的
environment variable
环境变量
Variable configuration
变量配置
It's in a hidden
是在一个隐藏的
In the document
文件里
find
找到
After home directory
主目录之后
Hold it down at the same time
大家同时按住
u201ccommand +  shift  + ."
“command +  shift  + ."
It will
就会
Show hidden files
显示出隐藏文件
And then we'll find out
然后大家再找到
The bash that starts with "."
以“."开头的这个bash
Profile
Profile
file
文件
namely
就是
MAC system
Mac系统的
environment variable
环境变量
configuration file
配置文件
This is what I configured
这里就是我配置的
MAC system environment variable
Mac系统环境变量
You find
大家找到
own
自己的
application program
应用程序
Just pick one
随便找一个
image
像
these ones here
这些
Maven
Maven
Let's see
大家看
This profile
这个配置文件
"maven"
"maven"
Find it
找到它的
That's it
就是这个
take
将
application
应用
Program directory
程序的目录
Start a prefix here
在这里起一个前缀名字
also
并且
Import
导入
Here is the "$" sign
这里是加“$"符
Not like
而不是像
win10
win10
Add a percent sign on both sides
在两边加百分号
Attention
大家要注意
There's a difference
是有区别的
After configuration
配置好之后
Keep it
大家保存
And
并在
Terminal command
终端命令
Input:
输入：
"source .bash_ profile"
"source .bash_profile"
That's it
这样就可以了
"mvn --version"
"mvn --version"
So the environment variables on the MAC system are
这样在Mac系统上的环境变量就
Just
就
It's configured
配置好了
You can
大家也可以
use
用
u201cvim"
“vim"
Configure
进行配置
VIM
vim
.
.
bash
bash
profile
profile
When inputting
输入的时候
Enter: "Iu201c
输入：“i"
then
然后
take
将
to configure
配置
Enter here
在这里输入
After input
输入之后
Press: ESC key
按下：esc 键
:
:
WQ
wq
!
!
sign out
退出
alike
同样的
source
source
It is also possible on the command side
在命令端也是可以的
In addition, we need to pay attention to
另外大家需要注意的是
If you are in a graphical interface
如果你在图形化界面
Can't find this file
找不到这个文件
Because this file is hidden
是因为这个文件是隐藏文件
No, everyone
大家不要
Forget to press
忘记按
"command
"command
+ shift
+ shift
+ ."
+ ."
Press and hold at the same time to display
同时按住就会显示出来
such
这样
Configuration of environment variables in MAC system
环境变量在Mac系统的配置
It's done
就完成了
Let's take a look at the Linux system
接下来我们再看一下在Linux的系统
With MAC
跟Mac系统
The difference between
的区别
Let's open it
我们打开
Folders for Linux systems
Linux 系统的文件夹
Also find "home directory"
同样找到“主目录”
We need
大家需要
stay
在
Upper right corner
右上角
Check show hidden files
勾选显示隐藏文件
also
并且
find
找到
Beginning with "."
以“."开头的
Bash file
bash 文件
Let's search
我们搜索一下
.
.
bash
bash
RC
rc
This is the document
这是这个文件
It's not the same as the MAC file name
跟Mac系统的文件名字是不一样的
We
我们
Open with a text editor
用文本编辑器打开（它）
You'll also see
同样也会看到
On Linux
在Linux 系统上的
Environment variable configuration
环境变量配置
This environment variable follows the
这个环境变量跟
MAC system
Mac系统的
The method is the same
方法是一样的
Find your
找到你的
application program
应用程序
Of
的
catalog
目录
home directory
主目录
Configure a
配置一个
Home directory
“HOME”目录
hereunder
在下面
$sign
$ 符
Add bin directory
添加 bin 目录
also
并且
Save after adding
添加好之后保存
At the terminal, the same
在终端，同样的
input
输入
source
source
.
.
bash
bash
RC
rc
such
这样
That's it
就可以了
We can
我们也可以
Like: MAC system at terminal
像： mac 系统在终端
like that
那样
u201cvim .bashrc"
“vim .bashrc"
Edit on the command line
在命令行里编辑
It's ok
也是可以的
In Linux system, you can quickly
在Linux 系统可以快速的
find
找到
You installed
你安装的
program
程序
For example:
比如：
We input
我们输入
type
type
java
java
You'll find it quickly
就会快速的找到
Installed programs
安装的程序
catalog
目录
Then configure
然后进行配置
it's fine too
也可以
"whereis
"whereis
After Java "
java " 之后
Reenter
再输入
u201cls -lrt"
“ls -lrt"
take
将
this
这个
Execution command of bin directory
bin目录的执行命令
Paste it here
粘贴过来
same
同样
You can also find it
也可以找到
its
它的
Installation directory
安装目录
Or
或者用
which
which
java
java
You can also find it
也可以找到
The difference is
区别就是
Linux system follows
Linux系统跟
MAC system
Mac系统的
configuration file
配置文件
name
名字
dissimilarity
不一样
You need to pay attention
大家需要注意一下
In this way, the environment variables of Linux system
这样在Linux系统的环境变量
So it's configured
也就配置好了
When you use VIM, you need to pay attention to: you can't use VIM without installation, you need to use vim
大家在使用vim时需要注意:如果没有安装是不能使用的,大家需要使用
"Sudo apt install VIM" for Mac
“Sudo apt install vim“, 如果是Mac系统就输入
Brew install VIM; for example, CentOS or other systems, change "apt install VIM" to "Yum install VIM"u201c
brew install vim;像：centos 或者其它系统,将 "apt install vim" 改成 "yum install vim“
Or other orders, that's all
或者其它命令，就可以了
Thank you for watching! If you are interested in my video
感谢大家的收看！如果你对我的视频感兴趣
Just
就
give the thumbs-up
点赞
And subscribe to my channel
并且订阅我的频道
Press the little bell
按下小铃铛
Highlights
精彩内容
Don't miss it
不容错过
thank you!
谢谢！